Hey everybody, welcome to the content
video for section 8.7, Searching
for Substrings. This is actually
pretty similar to something
we've talked about before with
strings operating a lot like lists.
And some of the functionality
that we can do in a string
is going to be really,
really similar to what we can
do in lists. So let's go
ahead and jump over to our
code space and we'll kind of
talk through some examples.
This was the example that they
gave in the textbook and I thought
I'd just save us a minute by
pasting it over instead of typing
it out with you watching. So here
we have a phrase to be or not
to be. That is the question. And
I want to search for the substring
two because it appears so often.
So I'm going to make a count
and set that equal to phrase.count2.
And then let's just print out the count.
See how many times we get it.
All right, we have it twice.
to be or not to be that is the
question so we got it right um
and then what we could do is
if we were you know we've got
our um we've got two instances
of this of the string showing
up so what we could do is we
can count it using a specific
index in the count function
which I believe it talks about
over in this section. Let me,
yeah, so we can, if we wanted to
find a count from a specific index,
sorry, we can use the start index
and an end index in the count
function. So we could say count equals
phrase dot count. Let's look for
the same word again too, and then,
let's see, so strings are going
to be indexed the same way that
lists are, but each word is in its
own element, each character is its
own element. So let's start counting
from, let's see, that's zero,
one. Let's start counting from the
first index, see how many instances
of count we, or of two we get.
We get one, so that's
about what we would expect
if we start counting after
the first occurrence.
We could also do it, let
me just copy this code,
counting from, let's see,
that's 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5,
6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13.
Let's count after the 13th
index, see how many instances
of 2 we get. Oh, maybe we
should start counting from 14.
There we go. So now we have
zero. We started counting after
both occurrences. So that's
kind of the count function.
There's also an index function
in strings that we can use. So
let's say index and we want to take
our phrase again. We're going to
use the index function and we're
going to give it the word two.
and let's print out the index.
See what it gives us.
Okay, the index of two is zero
because that's the first time it found
the word two. Now what about our
second one? Well, we can do a similar
thing with the count function as we
can with index is we can give it a
second argument there. Let me show
you, and maybe that'll make more
sense. So two, and then let's throw
in, let's see, where was that second?
Where was that 13? So I don't know.
Let's just throw in like 10 or something.
All right. So we start looking
after the 10th index point for
the next instance of the word
two. So kind of interesting. And
then the last thing that I wanted
to go over was the in operator,
which works really, really similar
to a way that a list would.
So if we want to find out, let's
say, who in phrase, we'll see if
that returns true. And it should
return true because it is in there.
um what if we said uh that that
should return false because the word
that oh my bad that isn't there
uh let's say what instead so that
returns false because the word
what is not in phrase All right, so
that's like kind of a brief summary
of finding substrings in strings.
There's a couple more methods
that we can use to find specific
instances of even smaller substrings
in strings, but that's all
that we'll go over for right
now, so thank you for watching.